{"question": "The 2023 Tokyo Marathon was the 16th edition of the annual marathon race in Tokyo, held on Sunday, 5 March 2023. A Platinum Label marathon, it was the first of six", "answer": "annual"}
{"question": "World news or international news or even foreign coverage is the news media jargon for news from abroad, about a country or a global subject. For journalism, it is a branch", "answer": "that"}
{"question": "Polaris Dawn is a planned private human spaceflight mission, operated by SpaceX on behalf of Shift4 Payments CEO Jared Isaacman, scheduled to launch no earlier than September 2023. The flight will", "answer": "be"}
{"question": "The Death of Jullebee Ranara, an Overseas Filipino Worker in Kuwait, was established to have occurred after her body was found buried in the desert on January 21, 2023. She was", "answer": "reportedly"}
{"question": "Kurentovanje 2023 is the upcoming 63rd Ptuj carnival, organized by Ptuj Tourism Public Institute. After two years of the pandemic and virtual events and self-initiated and spontaneously organized processions and parades", "answer": "around"}
{"question": "The 32nd Seoul Music Awards (Korean: 32nd 서울가요대상; RR: 32nd Seoul Gayo Daesang) is a award ceremony held on January 19, 2023. It was organized by Sports Seoul and broadcast through", "answer": "KBS"}
{"question": "On February 21, 2023, a mass shooting occurred at a bar in Sinop, Mato Grosso, Brazil. After losing R$20,000 (US$3,710.58) in a pool game, suspects Ezequias Souza Ribeiro and Edgar Ricardo", "answer": "de"}
{"question": "The 65th Annual Grammy Awards ceremony was a music awards ceremony held at the Crypto.com Arena in Los Angeles on February 5, 2023. It recognized the best recordings, compositions, and artists", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 2023 Coupe de France final was a football match between Nantes and Toulouse to decide the winner of the 2022–23 Coupe de France, the 106th season of the Coupe de", "answer": "France.Toulouse"}
{"question": "Devu G. versus State Of Kerala & Ors. (2023) is the case where Supreme Court granted special leave to appeal for a queer petitioner who received an unfavourable ruling in a", "answer": "High"}
{"question": "The 2023 IIHF World Championship Division I is an international ice hockey tournament run by the International Ice Hockey Federation.The Group A tournament is being held in Nottingham, United Kingdom from", "answer": "29"}
{"question": "The Salvadoran gang crackdown, referred to in El Salvador as the Régimen de Excepción (Spanish for State of Exception) and the Guerra Contra las Pandillas (Spanish for War Against the Gangs),", "answer": "began"}
{"question": "There has been a noted shortage of supply of sugar in the domestic market of the Philippines after a poor harvest of for the 2021–22 crop year. This led to the", "answer": "price"}
{"question": "The 2023 State of the Union Address was given by the 46th president of the United States, Joe Biden, on Tuesday, February 7, 2023, at 9:00 p.m. EST, in the chamber", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 75th Primetime Emmy Awards will honor the best in American prime time television programming from June 1, 2022, until May 31, 2023, as chosen by the Academy of Television Arts", "answer": "&"}
{"question": "General elections were held in Paraguay on 30 April 2023. Incumbent president Mario Abdo Benítez and vice president Hugo Velázquez Moreno of the Colorado Party were ineligible from seeking re-election. Colorado", "answer": "candidate"}
{"question": "The Reddings was an American funk, soul and disco band, founded by Otis Redding's sons Dexter (bass and vocals) and Otis Redding III (December 17, 1963 – April 18, 2023 age", "answer": "59;"}
{"question": "On 22 February 2023, at roughly 8pm local time, two gunmen shot off-duty Detective Chief Inspector John Caldwell in Omagh, Northern Ireland. The gunmen are believed to have been linked to", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The XIX Island Games (also known as the 2023 NatWest Island Games for sponsorship reasons) were to have been held in Guernsey, Channel Islands in 2021 however due to the COVID-19", "answer": "pandemic"}
{"question": "The 2023 Al-Aqsa clashes were a series of violent confrontations that occurred between Palestinians and Israeli police at the Al-Aqsa Mosque in Jerusalem in April 2023. After the evening Ramadan prayer,", "answer": "Palestinians"}
{"question": "In March 2023, pro-Khalistan Sikhs protested across the United States, the United Kingdom, Australia, Canada and Punjab, India, against the manhunt of the pro-Khalistan activist Amritpal Singh and crackdown on his", "answer": "organisation"}
{"question": "The 2022–23 season is the 143rd competitive association football season in England. The season began in July 2022 due to the 2022 FIFA World Cup taking place from 20 November to", "answer": "18"}
{"question": "The 1st Ikon Awards ceremony, presented by the Sauti Plus Hub, honored Ugandan films released from 2021 and 2022, and took place at the Kampala Serena Hotel in Kampala, Uganda, on", "answer": "March"}
{"question": "Brit Awards 2023, the 43rd edition of the ceremony, presented by the British Phonographic Industry (BPI), was held on 11 February 2023 to recognise the best in British and international music.", "answer": "The"}
{"question": "The 2023 Census of Nigeria will be a detailed enumeration of the Nigerian population that will be the fifth national census in the country since Independence. It will be the first", "answer": "national"}
{"question": "Stardom New Blood 7 (スターダムニューブラッド7, Sutādamunyūburaddo 7) was a professional wrestling event promoted by World Wonder Ring Stardom. The event took place on January 20, 2023, in Tokyo, Japan at the", "answer": "Belle"}
{"question": "On 26 February 2023, an unidentified person fatally shot two Israeli settlers in their car in Huwara, a town south of Nablus in the Israeli-occupied West Bank. Following the shooting, Israeli", "answer": "settlers"}
{"question": "Dark Angel is an American thrash metal band from Downey, California, that formed in 1981. The band's current lineup includes drummer Gene Hoglan, guitarists Eric Meyer and Laura Christine, frontman Ron", "answer": "Rinehart"}
{"question": "The Geostationary Defense and Strategic Communications Satellite 2 or SGDC-2 (in Portuguese: Satélite Geoestacionário de Defesa e Comunicações Estratégicas 2) is a Brazilian geostationary communication satellite that is currently in the", "answer": "planning"}
{"question": "The 2023 IBA World Boxing Championships are held in Tashkent, Uzbekistan from 30 April to 14 May 2023. Athletes from all five continents take part in the championship. Boxers compete for", "answer": "medals"}
{"question": "On 10 January 2023, Constantine II of Greece, Head of the Royal House of Greece, who reigned as the last King of the Hellenes from 6 March 1964 to 1 June", "answer": "1973,"}
{"question": "The 7th Crunchyroll Anime Awards was held on March 4, 2023, at the Main Banquet Hall of the Grand Prince Hotel New Takanawa in Tokyo, Japan. It was the first ceremony", "answer": "to"}
{"question": "Operation Wuambushu (\"recovery\" in Shimaore) is an ongoing French military-police operation in Mayotte, aimed at expelling illegal aliens, destroying slums, and fighting crime on the island.The operation was revealed on February", "answer": "22,"}
{"question": "In March 2023, a major fire broke out at the 110-acre Bhrahmapuram landfill site at Bhrahmapuram in Vadavukot-Puthankurish Panchayat, 17 km away from Kochi city. The fire began on 2 March", "answer": "2023"}
{"question": "8Turn (Korean: 에잇턴; stylized in all caps) is a South Korean boy band formed by MNH Entertainment. The group currently consists of eight members: Myungho, Jaeyun, Minho, Yoonsung, Haemin, Kyungmin, Yungyu", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "Indian Data Relay Satellite System or IDRSS is a planned Indian constellation of Inter-satellite communications satellites. It is planned to initially comprise two satellites, CMS-04 (formerly IDRSS-1) & IDRSS-2 in geostationary", "answer": "orbit."}
{"question": "The 15th Negeri Sembilan state election will be held in 2023 to elect the State Assembly members of the 15th Negeri Sembilan State Legislative Assembly, the legislature of the Malaysian state", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 2023 Nouakchott prison break was the result of a prison riot in the Nouakchott Civil Prison, the central prison of Mauritania. Four AQMI members managed to escape from the Nouakchott", "answer": "civil"}
{"question": "Eurovision Choir 2023 will be the third Eurovision Choir competition for choral singers, organised by the European Broadcasting Union (EBU) and Interkultur. Latvia will host the event for the second time.", "answer": "The"}
{"question": "The 2023 Madrid Open (sponsored by Mutua) is a professional tennis tournament to be played on outdoor clay courts at the Park Manzanares in Madrid, Spain from 25 April to 7", "answer": "May"}
{"question": "The 24th Annual Latin Grammy Awards will take place in November 2023 in Seville, Spain. The awards will honor recordings released between June 1, 2022, and May 31, 2023. It will", "answer": "mark"}
{"question": "On 26 January 2023, the Israel Border Police and the Israeli army conducted an armed raid on the Jenin refugee camp, which is in Area A of the Israeli-occupied West Bank", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "The 2022-2023 Pakistan economic crisis is an ongoing economic crisis and part of 2022-2023 political unrest in Pakistan. It has caused severe economic challenges for months due to which food, gas", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "The 2023 La Vuelta Femenina (officially La Vuelta Femenina by Carrefour.es), will be the first edition of the La Vuelta Femenina, a cycling stage race taking place in Spain. The race", "answer": "is"}
{"question": "Sumika (stylized as sumika) is a Japanese rock band from Kawasaki, Kanagawa. The band formed as an indie rock band in 2013, before being signed to a major label in 2018.", "answer": "The"}
{"question": "On 20–22 March 2023, Xi Jinping, general secretary of the Chinese Communist Party and Chinese president, visited Russia, in his first international meeting since his re-election as president during the 2023", "answer": "National"}
{"question": "The 2023 Pan American Games (Spanish: Juegos Panamericanos de 2023), officially the XIX Pan American Games and commonly known as Santiago 2023, is a upcoming international multi-sport event governed by the", "answer": "Panam"}
{"question": "In journalism, local news refers to coverage of events, by the news, in a local context that would not be an interest of another locality, or otherwise be of national or", "answer": "international"}
{"question": "The 2022 All Africa Music Awards (also known as AFRIMA) was scheduled to be held on December 8 to 11, 2022. But, it was announced that the ceremony would be held", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "The International Year of Basic Sciences for Sustainable Development was proclaimed by the 76th session of the United Nations General Assembly 2 December 2021 for 2022, stressing that the applications of", "answer": "basic"}
{"question": "Triangle Derby I was the first annual round-robin six-woman tag team tournament event promoted by World Wonder Ring Stardom under the \"Triangle Derby\" branch. The event took place between January 3", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "2023 Gagauz gubernatorial election will be held on 30 April 2023 on the territory of the Autonomous Territorial Unit of Gagauzia, part of the Republic of Moldova. The position of Governor", "answer": "(Başkan)"}
{"question": "The 2023 Nobel Peace Prize is an international peace prize established according to Alfred Nobel's will that will be announced on October 2023 by the Norwegian Nobel Committee in Oslo, Norway,", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "A series of civil unrest incidents began in France on 19 January 2023, organised by opponents of the pension reform bill proposed by the Borne government, which would increase the retirement", "answer": "age"}
{"question": "The 76th British Academy Film Awards, more commonly known as the BAFTAs, were held on 19 February 2023, honouring the best national and foreign films of 2022, at the Royal Festival", "answer": "Hall"}
{"question": "The Swedish Centre Party's party leadership election was held at an extraordinary party meeting on 2 February 2023 in Helsingborg. The Centre Party nominated Muharrem Demirok to succeed to outgoing party", "answer": "leader"}
{"question": "The 19th Irish Film & Television Academy Awards, also called the IFTA Film & Drama Awards 2023 or the 20th Anniversary IFTA Awards, will take place on 7 May 2023, hosted", "answer": "by"}
{"question": "On 26 February 2023, a boat carrying migrants sank amidst harsh weather conditions while trying to land on the coast of Steccato di Cutro, a seaside resort village near the town", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 2023 Metro FM Music Awards is the 17th annual ceremony of the Metro FM Music Awards, the ceremony is sponsored by Metro FM and is set to premiere live on", "answer": "SABC1"}
{"question": "General elections will be held in Cambodia on 23 July 2023 to elect members of the National Assembly. It will be the seventh quinquennial election in Cambodia since democratic elections were", "answer": "restored"}
{"question": "Man of the World 2023 will be the 5th edition of the Man of the World pageant. It will be held in the Philippines on June 16. Aditya Khurana of India", "answer": "will"}
{"question": "Quarteto em Cy (a play on words of the Portuguese for Quartet in B by poet and lyricist Vinicius de Moraes) is a Brazilian girl group originally composed of four sisters", "answer": "hailing"}
{"question": "The 16th Congress of the Popular Front for the Liberation of Saguia El Hamra and Río de Oro (Arabic: المؤتمر السادس عشر للجبهة الشعبية لتحرير الساقية الحمراء ووادي الذهب, Spanish: XVI", "answer": "Congreso"}
{"question": "Miss Grand South Africa 2023 will be the eighth edition of the Miss Grand South Africa beauty pageant, scheduled to be held on July 22, 2023, at the Atterbury Theatre in", "answer": "South"}
{"question": "The 2023 Guatemala City mayoral election will be held on 25 June 2023, to elect the mayor of Guatemala City, Department of Guatemala and thirteen members of the Municipal Council. Incumbent", "answer": "Ricardo"}
{"question": "The 2023 United Kingdom pupil protests were a series of protests, demonstrations and riots which occurred across secondary schools in the United Kingdom in February and March 2023. The protests were", "answer": "held"}
{"question": "The 16th Asian Film Awards was held on March 12, 2023 at Hong Kong Jockey Club Auditorium in Hong Kong Palace Museum. The nominations were announced on January 6, 2023. At", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The Tar Taing massacre was a mass killing of civilians by Burmese military forces between 1 and 2 March 2023, in the village of Tadaing (variously spelt Tataing, Tar Taing, Tatai,", "answer": "Tartaing,"}
{"question": "On 2 April 2023, a bombing occurred in the Street Food Bar №1 café on Universitetskaya Embankment in Saint Petersburg, Russia. Russian military blogger Vladlen Tatarsky, real name Maxim Fomin, died", "answer": "as"}
{"question": "The 75th Directors Guild of America Awards, honoring the outstanding directorial achievement in feature films, documentary, television and commercials of 2022, were presented on February 18, 2023. The ceremony was hosted", "answer": "by"}
{"question": "The 2023 United Nations Climate Change Conference or Conference of the Parties of the UNFCCC, more commonly referred to as COP28, will be the 28th United Nations Climate Change conference, held", "answer": "from"}
{"question": "Shenzhou 16 (Chinese: 神舟十六号; pinyin: Shénzhōu Shí'liù-hào; lit. 'Divine Boat Number 16') is a planned Chinese spaceflight to the Tiangong space station, expected to launch in May 2023 on board a", "answer": "Shenzhou"}
{"question": "The United Nations High Seas Treaty is an instrument of the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS), agreed by an intergovernmental conference at the UN on 4", "answer": "March"}
{"question": "The 2023 DFB-Pokal Final will decide the winner of the 2022–23 DFB-Pokal, the 80th season of the annual German football cup competition. The match will be played on 3 June 2023", "answer": "at"}
{"question": "The 58th Academy of Country Music Awards will be held on May 11, 2023, in Frisco, Texas at the Ford Center at The Star. The ceremony will be hosted by country", "answer": "legends"}
{"question": "The 2023 Princess Auto Players' Championship was held from April 11 to 16 at the Mattamy Athletic Centre in Toronto, Ontario. It was the fifth Grand Slam event and final major", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "A Marburg virus disease outbreak in Tanzania was first reported on 21 March 2023 by the Ministry of Health of Tanzania. This is the first time that Tanzania has reported an", "answer": "outbreak"}
{"question": "The Lucha Libre World Cup was a professional wrestling event and tournament organized by Mexican professional wrestling promotion Lucha Libre AAA Worldwide (AAA). The tournament took place on March 19, 2023", "answer": "at"}
{"question": "The 2023 New Zealand census, which took place on 7 March 2023, was the thirty-fifth national census in New Zealand. It implemented measures that aimed to increase the Census' effectiveness in", "answer": "response"}
{"question": "Action Plan against Disinformation (Czech: Akční plán pro čelení dezinformacím) was a material that was prepared by the government commissioner for media and disinformation Michal Klíma and his team of experts", "answer": "at"}
{"question": "The Second European Political Community Summit is a planned meeting of the European Political Community to be held on 1 June 2023 at Mimi Castle, Bulboaca 35 km from Chișinău, Moldova.", "answer": "It"}
{"question": "The 50th ceremony of the Annie Awards, honoring excellence in the field of animation for the year of 2022, was held on February 25, 2023, at the University of California, Los", "answer": "Angeles's"}
{"question": "The Nairobi Declaration (Arabic إعــــــــــلان نيـــــــروبي) is an ongoing attempt by a group of South Sudanese military officials led by rebel deputy chief of staff Dickson Gatluak Jock to remove Paul", "answer": "Malong"}
{"question": "A by-election was held in the Vaimauga 3 constituency in Samoa on 24 February 2023. The by-election was triggered by the death of the incumbent member of parliament Tapunuu Niko Lee", "answer": "Hang"}
{"question": "The 2023 Belgian Cup Final, named Croky Cup after the sponsor, will be the 68th Belgian Cup final and is scheduled to be played on 30 April 2023. KV Mechelen qualified", "answer": "for"}
{"question": "The 2022–23 North American winter was an unusually warm winter for the east and an unusually cold winter for the west in North America, as it occurred across the continent from", "answer": "late"}
{"question": "The 10th Platino Awards, presented by the Entidad de Gestión de Derechos de los Productores Audiovisuales (EGEDA) and the Federación Iberoamericana de Productores Cinematográficos y Audiovisuales (FIPCA), took place on 22", "answer": "April"}
{"question": "A media monitoring service, a press clipping service or a clipping service as known in earlier times, provides clients with copies of media content, which is of specific interest to them", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "Tropical Cyclone Cheneso was a strong tropical cyclone that affected Madagascar in January 2023. The fourth tropical storm and fifth tropical cyclone of the 2022–23 South-West Indian Ocean cyclone season, Cheneso", "answer": "developed"}
{"question": "Wallenius Lines is a privately owned Swedish shipping company. The company was founded in 1934 by Olof Wallenius. Wallenius Lines is an investor and active owner within the global shipping industry,", "answer": "specifically"}
{"question": "Lithuania is scheduled to participate in the Eurovision Song Contest 2023 in Liverpool, United Kingdom, with \"Stay\" performed by Monika Linkytė. The Lithuanian broadcaster, Lietuvos radijas ir televizija (LRT), used the", "answer": "national"}
{"question": "The Dublin Airport drone incidents are a number of incursions of drones into airspace around Dublin Airport, including a series in early 2023, which caused disruption of airport operations. It is", "answer": "illegal"}
{"question": "Geneina (sometimes Al-Junaynah or El Geneina; Arabic: الجنينة, lit. the little garden) is a city in West Darfur, part of dar Masalit region, that joined British Sudan at the end of", "answer": "1919"}
{"question": "An online newsroom (also known as a pressroom, mediaroom, press center or media center) is a website, web page or site section that contains distributable information about a corporation or organization.", "answer": "The"}
{"question": "Triplemanía XXXI is an ongoing three-day professional wrestling pay-per-view (PPV) event promoted and produced by the Mexican professional wrestling promotion Lucha Libre AAA Worldwide (AAA or Triple A). The event is", "answer": "being"}
{"question": "A by-election was held in the Tongan electorate of Tongatapu 8 on 19 January 2023. The by-election was triggered by the death of Semisi Fakahau on 27 October 2022. The election", "answer": "was"}
{"question": "An indirect presidential election was held in Vietnam on 2 March 2023. The election took place early following the resignation of President Nguyễn Xuân Phúc as part of a broad anti-corruption", "answer": "purge"}
{"question": "Municipal elections are set to be held in Israel on 31 October 2023. In accordance with changes made in 2018, election day will be a paid day off work. All municipalities,", "answer": "local"}
{"question": "The 15th Penang state election will be held in 2023 to elect the State Assembly members of the 15th Penang State Legislative Assembly, the legislature of the Malaysian state of Penang.", "answer": "Penang"}
{"question": "The 80th Golden Globe Awards honored the best in film and American television of 2022, as chosen by the Hollywood Foreign Press Association (HFPA). The ceremony was held on January 10,", "answer": "2023,"}
{"question": "The 2023 Toronto mayoral by-election will be held on Monday, June 26, 2023, to elect a candidate to serve as the mayor of Toronto for the remainder of the 2022–2026 city", "answer": "council"}
{"question": "The 2023 British Academy Television Awards will be held on 14 May 2023 at the Royal Festival Hall in London, to recognise the excellence in British television of 2022. The nominations", "answer": "were"}
{"question": "Entertainment journalism is any form of journalism that focuses on popular culture and the entertainment business and its products. Like fashion journalism, entertainment journalism covers industry-specific news while targeting general audiences", "answer": "beyond"}
{"question": "Miss Grand Japan 2023 will be the ninth edition of the Miss Grand Japan beauty pageant, scheduled to be held on July 16, 2023, at the Tokyo FM Hall of the", "answer": "Tokyo"}
{"question": "A series of protests against the Nigerian Naira and the 2023 Nigerian presidential election began on February 4 due to the Nigerian Naira, protests due to the election are still occurring", "answer": "as"}
{"question": "Many journalists compared the events of the 2023 Brazilian Congress attack to the January 6 United States Capitol attack. Several newspapers, including O Globo, Veja, and Folha de S.Paulo, characterised what", "answer": "happened"}
{"question": "On 2 March 2023, the Russian authorities said that an armed Ukrainian group crossed the border and attacked the villages of Lyubechane and Sushany, in Bryansk Oblast. Russia said the attackers", "answer": "fired"}
{"question": "All Star Junior Festival 2023 was an interpromotional professional wrestling pay-per-view event organized by New Japan Pro-Wrestling (NJPW). It was held on March 1, 2023 at Korakuen Hall in Bunkyo, Tokyo,", "answer": "Japan."}
{"question": "The 2022–23 season is the 118th season in the existence of Galatasaray and the club's 65th consecutive season in the top flight of Turkish football. In addition to the domestic league,", "answer": "Galatasaray"}
{"question": "Tailte Éireann (lit. 'Irish Lands') is a state agency in Ireland responsible for property registrations, property valuation and national mapping services. It was established on 1 March 2023 from a merger", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "Severe Tropical Cyclone Gabrielle was a severe tropical cyclone that devastated the North Island of New Zealand and affected parts of Vanuatu and Australia in February 2023. It is the costliest", "answer": "tropical"}
{"question": "The 37th Golden Disc Awards (Korean: 37th 골든 디스크 시상식; RR: 37th Goldeun diseukeu sisangsik) is a award ceremony held on January 7, 2023, and broadcast through various television networks and", "answer": "streaming"}
{"question": "The 38th Film Independent Spirit Awards, honoring the best independent films and television series of 2022, were presented by Film Independent on March 4, 2023. The film nominations were announced live", "answer": "via"}
{"question": "An explosion occurred on April 10, 2023, at the South Fork Dairy Farm in Dimmitt, Texas, United States. The explosion and subsequent fire killed approximately 18,000 cows and injured one person.", "answer": "The"}
{"question": "The 2023 Chinese presidential election (Chinese: 2023年中国国家主席选举) was held on 10 March 2023, at the 14th National People's Congress to indirectly elect the President and the Vice President of China. The", "answer": "President"}
{"question": "Prabowo Subianto's presidential campaign in 2024 is his third bid for the presidency of Indonesia. For his third bid, his party, Gerindra Party, formed a coalition with the National Awakening Party", "answer": "on"}
{"question": "The 2023 Vilnius summit is an upcoming NATO summit scheduled to take place on 11-12 July 2023, in Vilnius, the capital of Lithuania. The summit was officially proposed during the 2022", "answer": "Madrid"}
{"question": "Progress MS-23 (Russian: Прогресс МC-23), Russian production No.453, identified by NASA as Progress 84P, is a Progress spaceflight launched by Roscosmos to resupply the International Space Station (ISS). It is the", "answer": "174rd"}
{"question": "The APRA Music Awards of 2023 are the upcoming 41st annual series, known as the APRA Awards. The awards are given in a series of categories in three divisions and in", "answer": "separate"}
{"question": "Miss Universe Philippines 2023 will be the fourth edition of the Miss Universe Philippines competition. The coronation night will be held on May 13, 2023, at the SM Mall of Asia", "answer": "Arena"}
{"question": "The 2023 NBA playoffs is the ongoing postseason tournament of the National Basketball Association's 2022–23 season. The playoffs began on April 15 and will end with the conclusion of the 2023", "answer": "NBA"}
{"question": "The Golden Jubilee of Carl XVI Gustaf will be celebrated in 2023 in the Kingdom of Sweden, to mark the 50th anniversary of the accession of King Carl XVI Gustaf on", "answer": "15"}
{"question": "At around 6:10 PM EDT on April 26, 2023, what was later determined to be an improvised explosive device exploded in Weare, New Hampshire at a home on NH Route 77.", "answer": "ATF"}
{"question": "In 2022, heavy tensions broke out between the Democratic Republic of the Congo and Rwanda, which have led to several alleged attacks by Congolese and Rwandan forces on each other's territory.", "answer": "Rwandan"}
{"question": "The 2023 New Year Honours in New Zealand were appointments by Charles III in his right as King of New Zealand, on the advice of the New Zealand government, to various", "answer": "orders"}
{"question": "Cream Soda is a Russian electronic music group founded in 2012. The members of the group write the music and the lyrics to the songs, sing and play live in concerts.", "answer": "On"}
{"question": "BabyMonster (Korean: 베이비몬스터; stylized in all caps), also known as Baemon, (Korean: 베몬) is an upcoming South Korean girl group formed by YG Entertainment. Consisting of seven members—Ruka, Pharita, Asa, Ahyeon,", "answer": "Haram,"}
{"question": "The 2023 WWE Hall of Fame was a professional wrestling event produced by WWE that featured the induction of the 24th class into the WWE Hall of Fame. The ceremony took", "answer": "place"}
{"question": "The 2023 Australia Day Honours are appointments to various orders and honours to recognise and reward good works by Australian citizens. The list was announced on 26 January 2023 by the", "answer": "Governor"}
{"question": "The wedding of Hussein, Crown Prince of Jordan, and Rajwa Al Saif will take place on 1 June 2023 in the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan. Hussein is the eldest son and", "answer": "heir"}
{"question": "The 19th British Academy Video Game Awards were hosted by the British Academy of Film and Television Arts on 30 March 2023 to honour the best video games of 2022. Held", "answer": "at"}
{"question": "The Kyiv summit in 3 February 2023 will be an important event in EU-Ukraine bilateral relations due to the Russian invasion of Ukraine in 2022. The meeting will be hosted by", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "An airstrike, suspected to have been carried out by the Israeli Air Force, targeted sites in the Damascus Governorate, including a residential building. Five fatalities and fifteen injuries have been reported,", "answer": "with"}
{"question": "In the parliamentary elections in Andorra on 2 April 2023, the incumbent liberal-conservative coalition between Democrats for Andorra (DA) and Committed Citizens (CC) won an absolute majority led by Prime Minister", "answer": "Xavier"}
{"question": "Pesma za Evroviziju '23 was the second edition of Pesma za Evroviziju, Serbia's national final organised by Radio Television of Serbia (RTS) to select the Serbian entry for the Eurovision Song", "answer": "Contest"}
{"question": "The Inauguration of Petr Pavel as President of the Czech Republic took place on 9 March 2023 at a ceremonial joint meeting of both chambers of the Parliament of the Czech", "answer": "Republic"}
{"question": "The 2023 EuroCup Basketball Playoffs began on 11 April with the eighthfinals and will be ending with the final, to decide the champions of the 2022–23 EuroCup Basketball. A total of", "answer": "16"}
{"question": "Miss Philippines Earth 2023 was the 23rd edition of the Miss Philippines Earth pageant, it was held at the Toledo City Sports Center in Toledo, Cebu, Philippines on April 29, 2023.At", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The Whispers is an American group from Los Angeles, California, who have scored hit records since the late 1960s. They are best known for their two number one R&B singles, \"And", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The Swedish anti-terrorism bill of 2023 refers to the anti-terrorism legislation debated by the Swedish parliament. The new legislation has been first proposed in 2017 following the Stockholm truck attack and", "answer": "would"}
{"question": "Beginning on 31 July 2022, tensions between Serbia and Kosovo heightened due to the expiration of the eleven-year validity period of documents for cars on 1 August 2022, between the government", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 24th Annual British Academy Television Craft Awards took place on 23 April 2023 at The Brewery in London, presented by the British Academy of Film and Television Arts (BAFTA) to", "answer": "recognize"}
{"question": "The 2023 Nigerian House of Representatives elections were held on 25 February 2023 where voters elected members of the House of Representatives using first-past-the-post voting in all 360 federal constituencies. The", "answer": "last"}
{"question": "The Streamlining Energy Efficiency for Schools Act of 2014 (H.R. 4092) is a bill that would require the United States Department of Energy to establish a centralized clearinghouse to disseminate information", "answer": "on"}
{"question": "The Northern Rocky Mountains ecosystem in the United States is known by ecologists, biologists, and naturalists as one of the last areas of the contiguous United States that is relatively undeveloped", "answer": "enough"}
{"question": "Soyuz MS-23 is an uncrewed Russian Soyuz spaceflight that launched from Baikonur on 24 February 2023 to the International Space Station, in order to replace the Soyuz MS spacecraft for landing", "answer": "that"}
{"question": "Miss Universe Colombia 2023 will be the 3rd edition of the Miss Universe Colombia pageant, to be held in Colombia. María Fernanda Aristizabal Urrea of Quindio will crown her successor at", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 8th Annual Latin American Music Awards was held on April 20, 2023, to recognize outstanding achievements for artists in the Latin music industry of 2022, voted by the public.The ceremony", "answer": "will"}
{"question": "A disease outbreak was first reported in Equatorial Guinea on 7 February 2023 and, on 13 February 2023, it was identified as being Marburg virus disease. It was the first time", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "Live at Bush Hall is a concert film by British rock band Black Country, New Road released on 20 February 2023 through YouTube. It is the first official release since Ants", "answer": "from"}
{"question": "The 44th Sports Emmy Awards will be presented by the National Academy of Television Arts and Sciences (NATAS), honoring the best in American sports television coverage in 2022. The ceremony will", "answer": "take"}
{"question": "General elections were held in the British Virgin Islands on 24 April 2023.The initial results indicated that no party had won overall control of the House of Assembly. The incumbent Virgin", "answer": "Islands"}
{"question": "Expedition 69 is the 69th long-duration expedition to the International Space Station. The expedition began with the departure of Soyuz MS-22 in March 2023 with Russian cosmonaut Sergey Prokopyev continuing his", "answer": "ISS"}
{"question": "Göktürk-3 is a synthetic aperture radar (SAR) Earth observation satellite that will be designed and developed under prime contractorship of Turkish Aerospace Industries (TAI) with support of Military Electronic Industries (ASELSAN)", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "On 18 September 2022, protests in Moldova began in the capital city of Chișinău, demanding the resignation of the country's pro-Western government, amid an energy crisis causing rising natural gas prices", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "The 2023–24 season will be the 119th season in the existence of Galatasaray and the club's 66th consecutive season in the top flight of Turkish football. In addition to the domestic", "answer": "league,"}
{"question": "The 2023 Stanley Cup playoffs is the ongoing playoff tournament of the National Hockey League (NHL) for the 2022–23 season. The playoffs began on April 17, 2023, three days after the", "answer": "end"}
{"question": "The 50th Daytime Emmy Awards, presented by the National Academy of Television Arts and Sciences (NATAS), will honor the best in U.S. daytime television programming in 2022. The award ceremony is", "answer": "planned"}
{"question": "Marchetti's constant is the average time spent by a person for commuting each day. Its value is approximately one hour, or half an hour for a one-way trip. It is named", "answer": "after"}
{"question": "Sakura Genesis was a professional wrestling event promoted by New Japan Pro-Wrestling (NJPW). The event took on April 8, 2023, in Tokyo at Ryōgoku Kokugikan. Previously held under the Invasion Attack", "answer": "name,"}
{"question": "Azymuth is a Brazilian jazz-funk group formed in 1973. The original lineup was a trio composed of José Roberto Bertrami (keyboards), Alex Malheiros (bass, guitars), and Ivan Conti (drums, percussion). Kiko", "answer": "Continentino"}
{"question": "Store bededag, translated literally as Great Prayer Day or more loosely as General Prayer Day, \"All Prayers\" Day, Great Day of Prayers or Common Prayer Day, is a Danish holiday celebrated", "answer": "on"}
{"question": "The 3rd Critics' Choice Super Awards, presented by the Critics Choice Association and honoring the best in genre fiction film and television. The nominees were announced on February 22, 2023. The", "answer": "winners"}
{"question": "The response of the United States to the ongoing Russian invasion of Ukraine that began in 2022 has been in favor of Ukraine. President Biden condemned the invasion, providing humanitarian and", "answer": "military"}
{"question": "Wrestle Kingdom 17 was a two-day professional wrestling pay-per-view (PPV) event co-produced by the New Japan Pro-Wrestling (NJPW) and Pro Wrestling Noah (Noah) promotions. The first day of the event took", "answer": "place"}
{"question": "The Agreement on the path to normalisation between Kosovo and Serbia, informally known as the Ohrid Agreement, is an agreement mediated by the European Union that aims to normalise diplomatic relations", "answer": "between"}
{"question": "The 2023 People's Choice Country Awards, the inaugural ceremony, is set to be held on September 28, 2023 at the Grand Ole Opry in Nashville, Tennessee. The ceremony will be broadcast", "answer": "live"}
{"question": "Local elections are being held in four municipalities in the north of Kosovo on 23 April 2023. They were initially scheduled to be held in December 2022 but were subsequently postoned.", "answer": "The"}
{"question": "On 6 February 2023 a referendum was held in the Wolayita, Gamo, Gofa, South Omo, Gedeo, and Konso Zones, as well as the Dirashe, Amaro, Burji, Ale, and Basketo special woredas", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 2023 iHeartRadio Music Awards were held at the Dolby Theatre in Los Angeles on March 27, 2023, and broadcast live on Fox. It was hosted by singer-songwriter and actor Lenny", "answer": "Kravitz."}
{"question": "A motion of no confidence in the Spanish government of Pedro Sánchez was tabled by the far-right party Vox on 27 February 2023, and will be debated and voted in the", "answer": "Congress"}
{"question": "The 43rd London Film Critics' Circle Awards honoured the best in film of 2022, as chosen by the London Film Critics' Circle. All films released in a UK cinema or to", "answer": "premiere"}
{"question": "The Nduga hostage crisis began on 7 February 2023 when Free Papua Movement (Indonesian: Organisasi Papua Merdeka, OPM) insurgents attacked a plane and took its pilot and all five passengers hostage.", "answer": "While"}
{"question": "On 3 April 2023, the Israeli army conducted a military operation in Nablus, resulting in the death of two Palestinians and injuries to several others. The operation was in response to", "answer": "allegations"}
{"question": "Starting in May 2022, postal workers in the United Kingdom undertook a series of strikes and industrial disputes. They principally involved members of Unite and the Communication Workers Union (CWU) at", "answer": "both"}
{"question": "San Marino is set to participate in the Eurovision Song Contest 2023 in Liverpool, United Kingdom, with \"Like an Animal\" performed by Piqued Jacks. The Sammarinese broadcaster San Marino RTV (SMRTV)", "answer": "organised"}
{"question": "On 21 March 2023, a magnitude 6.5 earthquake struck Badakhshan Province, Afghanistan, with an intermediate depth of approximately 187 km (116 mi). The epicenter of the earthquake was 40 km (25", "answer": "mi)"}
{"question": "Viscount Knollys (), of Caversham in the County of Oxford, is a title in the Peerage of the United Kingdom. It was created in 1911 for the court official Francis Knollys,", "answer": "1st"}
{"question": "The Juno Awards of 2023 was a music awards ceremony that was held on March 13, 2023 at Rogers Place in Edmonton, Alberta. It recognized the best recordings, compositions, and artists", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 2023 Chinese military exercises around Taiwan (simplified Chinese: 2023年环台军事演练; traditional Chinese: 2023年環台軍事演練) are a series of ongoing military exercises by the People's Liberation Army (PLA) of the People's Republic of", "answer": "China"}
{"question": "The 2023 Night of Champions is the upcoming 10th Night of Champions professional wrestling pay-per-view (PPV) and livestreaming event produced by the American promotion WWE. It will be held for wrestlers", "answer": "from"}
{"question": "The 2022–23 Toronto Maple Leafs season is the franchise's 106th season in the National Hockey League. On March 27, 2023, the Maple Leafs clinched a playoff spot after the Ottawa Senators", "answer": "defeated"}
{"question": "On the morning of 14 March 2023, a Russian Su-27 fighter jet intercepted and damaged an American MQ-9 Reaper drone, causing it to crash into the Black Sea. This became the", "answer": "first"}
{"question": "The 2023 AIR Awards is the upcoming seventeenth annual Australian Independent Record Labels Association Music Awards ceremony (generally known as the AIR Awards), scheduled to take place on 3 August 2023", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "The 36th Annual Nickelodeon Kids' Choice Awards ceremony was held on March 4, 2023, at the Microsoft Theater in Los Angeles, California with Nate Burleson and Charli D'Amelio serving as hosts.", "answer": "It"}
{"question": "The 2023 U-17 Africa Cup of Nations known as 2023 U17 AFCON for short and/or the TotalEnergies U-17 Africa Cup of Nations for sponsorship purposes is the 15th edition (20th if", "answer": "editions"}
{"question": "The 2023 Myanmar National League will be the fourteenth season of first-division domestic football in Myanmar. It will consist of twelve teams, as two teams from the 2022 MNL-2 were promoted.", "answer": "Shan"}
{"question": "The Global Pact for the Environment project was launched in 2017 by a network of experts known as the \"International Group of Experts for the Pact\" (IGEP). The group is made", "answer": "up"}
{"question": "The 2022–23 Basketball Champions League playoffs began on April 4, 2023, and concluded with the 2023 Basketball Champions League Final Four, to decide the champions of the 2022–23 Basketball Champions League.", "answer": "A"}
{"question": "A social media newsroom is a company resource, set up to increase the functionality and usability of the traditional online newsroom. Social media newsrooms (SMNs) are intended to encourage dialogue and", "answer": "information"}
{"question": "A radiation accident occurred in Prachin Buri Province, Thailand on 10 March 2023. When A cylinder, measuring 30 centimeters (4 inches) long and 13 centimeters (5 inches) wide, was reported missing", "answer": "during"}
{"question": "The Educational Irish Research Satellite 1 or EIRSAT-1 mission was proposed in response to the European Space Agency (ESA) FYS2 (Fly Your Satellite System 2) call. The proposal was led by", "answer": "University"}
{"question": "Puteri Indonesia 2023, (Lampungnese: , Javanese: ꦦꦸꦠꦺꦫꦶ​ꦆꦤ꧀ꦢꦺꦴꦤꦺꦱ​꧇꧒꧐꧒꧓꧇) the 26th Puteri Indonesia pageant, will be held on 19 May 2023 in Jakarta, Indonesia. Puteri Indonesia 2022, Laksmi Shari De-Neefe Suardana of Bali", "answer": "will"}
{"question": "The 2023 New Year Honours are appointments by some of the 15 Commonwealth realms to various orders and honours to recognise and reward good works by citizens of those countries. The", "answer": "New"}
{"question": "The 34th Producers Guild of America Awards (also known as 2023 Producers Guild Awards or 2023 PGA Awards), honoring the best film and television producers of 2022, were held at the", "answer": "Beverly"}
{"question": "Dear Liar, full title Dear Liar: A Comedy of Letters is a play by American actor, director, and playwright Jerome Kilty. It was first staged in 1957 and published in 1960.", "answer": "A"}
{"question": "From January 28 to February 4, 2023, a Chinese-operated high-altitude balloon was spotted in North American airspace, including Alaska, western Canada, and the contiguous United States. On February 4, the U.S.", "answer": "Air"}
{"question": "UN Member States are currently negotiating a legally-binding, international agreement on plastics that will address the entire life cycle of plastics, from design to production and disposal. On March 2, 2022", "answer": "UN"}
{"question": "Parliamentary elections are scheduled to be held in Slovakia on 30 September 2023 to elect members of the National Council. The 2020 Slovak parliamentary election resulted in a coalition government led", "answer": "by"}
{"question": "SpaceX CRS-28, also known as SpX-28, is a Commercial Resupply Service mission to the International Space Station (ISS) scheduled to be launched on 3 June 2023. The mission is contracted by", "answer": "NASA"}
{"question": "The COVID-19 Response Recognition Award is a service award established by the New Zealand government in 2022 to recognise individuals and organisations who contributed to New Zealand’s frontline workforce COVID-19 response.", "answer": "The"}
{"question": "On 19 April 2023, seven Palestinians were shot and injured by Israeli troops during a raid in the occupied West Bank. Conflicts and fatalities resulted in the area as a result", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 34th GLAAD Media Awards is the 2023 annual presentation of the GLAAD Media Awards, presented by GLAAD honoring the 2022 media season. They will be held on March 30, 2023", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "Parliamentary elections were held in Estonia on 5 March 2023 to elect all 101 members of the Riigikogu. The officially published election data indicate the victory of the Reform Party, which", "answer": "won"}
{"question": "The 2023 World Baseball Classic Pool B was the second of four pools of the 2023 World Baseball Classic that took place from March 9–13 at the Tokyo Dome in Tokyo,", "answer": "Japan."}
{"question": "On 19 April 2023, a crowd crush occurred in the Old City of Sanaa, the capital of Yemen, after people gathered in front of a school to receive the traditional alms", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 29th Annual Screen Actors Guild Awards, honoring the best achievements in film and television performances for the year 2022, were presented on February 26, 2023 at the Fairmont Century Plaza", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "The 28th Critics' Choice Awards were presented on January 15, 2023, at the Fairmont Century Plaza Hotel in Los Angeles, California, honoring the finest achievements of filmmaking and television programming in", "answer": "2022."}
{"question": "An indirect presidential election was held in Cuba on 19 April 2023. The election took place following the election to the National Assembly of People's Power on 26 March 2023. The", "answer": "incumbent"}
{"question": "The Bombay Sisters, C. Saroja (born 7 December 1936) and C. Lalitha (26 August 1938 – 31 January 2023), were an Indian Carnatic music singing duo. They received the Padma Shri,", "answer": "India's"}
{"question": "Miss USA 2023 will be the 72nd Miss USA pageant that will be held in 2023 at the Grand Sierra Resort in Reno, Nevada. Morgan Romano of North Carolina will crown", "answer": "her"}
{"question": "Snap legislative elections are scheduled to be held in Guinea-Bissau on 4 June 2023. Incumbent president Umaro Sissoco Embalo dissolved the parliament on 16 May 2022, accusing deputies of corruption and", "answer": "\"unresolvable\""}
{"question": "The 51st International Emmy Awards, presented by the International Academy of Television Arts and Sciences (IATAS), will honor the best in international television programming in 2022. Nominations are scheduled to be", "answer": "announced"}
{"question": "In April 2022, during the Russian invasion of Ukraine, an anti-war drawing of Maria Moskaylova, a sixth-grader in the Russian town of Yefremov, led to the political persecution of the girl", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "A constitutional referendum was planned to be held in Mali on 19 March 2023. It was initially scheduled for 9 July 2017. However, in late June it was postponed with no", "answer": "date"}
{"question": "The Pinlaung massacre was a mass killing of civilians by Burmese military forces on 11 March 2023, in the village of Namneng, Shan State. During the massacre, Myanmar Army troops killed", "answer": "at"}
{"question": "Fit for 55 is a package by the European Union designed to reduce the European Union's greenhouse gas emissions by 55% by 2030. The package was proposed in July 2021 by", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 2023 South American summit will be a summit organized and hosted by the government of Brazil \"to deal with the importance of seeking collective solutions in the name of a", "answer": "common"}
{"question": "On 23 March 2023, a boat sunk off the Tunisian coast, resulting in at least five dead and 34 missing migrants. The vessel was attempting to reach Italy, and it was", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "On 24 April 2023, an explosion in the Counter-Terrorism Department building in Kabal, Swat Valley, Pakistan, killed at least 17 people and wounded more than 50 others. Although the origin of", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 50th Annual Daytime Creative Arts Emmy Awards, presented by the National Academy of Television Arts and Sciences (NATAS), will honor the best in US daytime television programming in 2022. The", "answer": "award"}
{"question": "On February 11, 2023, NORAD, at the direction of the Canadian Minister of National Defence and Chief of the Defence Staff, downed an unidentified object over the Yukon.After snowfall in the", "answer": "area"}
{"question": "The 54th NAACP Image Awards, presented by the NAACP, honored outstanding representations and achievements of people of color in motion pictures, television, music, and literature during the 2022 calendar year. The", "answer": "ceremony"}
{"question": "Elections in Bangladesh in 2023 include election to the office of the President of Bangladesh, by-elections to the Jatiya Sangsad, elections to the 5 (five) City Corporation, several municipalities and local", "answer": "bodies."}
{"question": "Since May–June 2022, a series of labour strikes and industrial disputes have occurred in various industries of the United Kingdom's economy as workers walked out over pay and conditions. The strikes", "answer": "took"}
{"question": "The Good News International Ministries (GNIM), commonly known as the Malindi cult and previously as the Servant P. N. Mackenzie Ministries, is a new religious movement based in Shakahola, Kilifi, Kenya,", "answer": "that"}
{"question": "Strike! is a 2005 historical stage musical depicting the Winnipeg General Strike. It has been adapted into a Canadian Broadcasting Corporation radio production, a 17-minute short film, and the full-length feature", "answer": "film"}
{"question": "Intel Blockscale was a brand of crypto-mining accelerator ASIC sold by the U.S. chip manufacturer Intel. The Blockscale product debuted in June 2022, and was cancelled by Intel in April 2023.", "answer": "Intel"}
{"question": "On February 11, 2023, an octagonal unidentified flying object was detected over northern Montana. It disappeared until spotted the next day in Wisconsin, flying at 20,000 feet over the Upper Peninsula", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 2023 Backlash is the upcoming 18th Backlash professional wrestling pay-per-view (PPV) and livestreaming event produced by WWE. It will be held for wrestlers from the promotion's Raw and SmackDown brand", "answer": "divisions."}
{"question": "The 2023 FIBA Under-19 Women's Basketball World Cup is a tournament organised by FIBA for women's youth national teams aged 19 years old and below. The tournament will be hosted in", "answer": "Madrid,"}
{"question": "Miss Grand Ecuador 2023 was the second edition of the Miss Grand Ecuador beauty pageant, held at TC Televisión Studios, Guayaquil. It was originally proposed to be held in January but", "answer": "was"}
{"question": "The floods in South Africa in February-March 2023 were caused by heavy rainfall as a result of the La Niña weather phenomenon, affecting seven provinces, including Eastern Cape, Northern Cape, Mpumalanga,", "answer": "KwaZulu-Natal,"}
{"question": "Various countries and organizations have responded to the 6 February 2023 Turkey–Syria earthquake. At least 105 countries and 16 international organizations pledged support for victims of the earthquake, including humanitarian aid.", "answer": "More"}
{"question": "On 8 February 2023, Volodymyr Zelenskyy, the president of Ukraine, visited the United Kingdom. During his trip, Zelenskyy met Rishi Sunak, the prime minister of the United Kingdom. He also addressed", "answer": "Members"}
{"question": "The following are the appointments to various Canadian Honours of 2023. Usually, they are announced as part of the New Year and Canada Day celebrations and are published within the Canada", "answer": "Gazette"}
{"question": "The 38th Artios Awards, presented by the Casting Society of America, honoring the best originality, creativity and the contribution of casting to the overall quality of a film, television series, short", "answer": "film,"}
{"question": "The 2023 Madrid City Council election, also the 2023 Madrid municipal election, will be held on Sunday, 28 May 2023, to elect the 12th City Council of the municipality of Madrid.", "answer": "All"}
{"question": "The Exciters were an American pop music group of the 1960s. They were originally a girl group, with one male member being added afterwards. At the height of their popularity the", "answer": "group"}
{"question": "2023 International Horticultural Exposition or Expo 2023 is an International Horticultural Expo to be hosted by Doha, Qatar. The Horticultural Expo 2023 Doha will begin on October 2, 2023 and conclude", "answer": "on"}
{"question": "The 2022 Uganda Ebola outbreak was an outbreak of the Sudan ebolavirus, which causes Ebola, from 20 September 2022 until 10 January 2023 in the Western and Central Regions of Uganda.", "answer": "Over"}
{"question": "The removal of Indonesia as FIFA U-20 World Cup 2023 hosts was a political controversy that occurred in March 2023, when FIFA, the world governing body of association football, decided to", "answer": "strip"}
{"question": "Chinese Taipei or Taiwan is scheduled to compete at the 2022 Asian Games in Hangzhou, Zhejiang, China, from 23 September 2023 to 8 October 2023. However, due to the COVID-19 pandemic", "answer": "cases"}
{"question": "Local elections are scheduled to be held in Northern Ireland on 18 May 2023, two weeks after other elections across the United Kingdom. The last local elections in Northern Ireland were", "answer": "held"}
{"question": "An ongoing refugee crisis began in Africa in mid-April 2023 after the outbreak of the 2023 Sudan conflict. By 1 May 2023, an estimated 73,000 to 100,000 people [1] have fled", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "A news bureau is an office for gathering or distributing news. Similar terms are used for specialized bureaus, often to indicate a geographic location or scope of coverage: a ‘Tokyo bureau’", "answer": "refers"}
{"question": "On March 30, 2023, 63-year-old pensioner Mikhail Simonov was convicted due to two comments under other people's posts in the Russian social network VKontakte. Mikhail Simonov Alexei was accused of discrediting", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 2023 Bahrain Grand Prix (officially known as the Formula 1 Gulf Air Bahrain Grand Prix 2023) was a Formula One motor race that was held on 5 March 2023 at", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The Dazz Band is an American R&B/funk band most popular in the early 1980s. Emerging from Cleveland, Ohio, the group's biggest hit songs include \"Let It Whip\" (1982), \"Joystick\" (1983), and", "answer": "\"Let"}
{"question": "An Honours List on The Demise of Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II, known as the Demise Honours, was released on 25 March 2023, following the death of Elizabeth II in 2022.", "answer": "It"}
{"question": "The 2023 Games of the Small States of Europe, also known as the XIX Games of the Small States of Europe or informally Malta 2023, is an upcoming sporting event, scheduled", "answer": "to"}
{"question": "An ongoing refugee crisis began in Europe in late February 2022 after Russia's invasion of Ukraine. Over 8.1 million refugees fleeing Ukraine have been recorded across Europe, while an estimated 8", "answer": "million"}
{"question": "The 12th Circle Chart Music Awards ceremony was held at KSPO Dome in Seoul on February 18, 2023, to recognise the best artists and recordings, primarily based on Circle Music Chart", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "Parliamentary elections were held in the Federated States of Micronesia on 7 March 2023 to elect the fourteen members of the Congress: ten representatives of the districts, and four senators each", "answer": "representing"}
{"question": "During the 2023 Sudan conflict the outbreak of violence has led foreign governments to monitor the situation in Sudan and move towards the evacuation and repatriation of its nationals. Among some", "answer": "countries"}
{"question": "The 15th Terengganu state election will be held in 2023 to elect the State Assembly members of the 15th Terengganu State Legislative Assembly, the legislature of the Malaysian state of Terengganu.", "answer": "Terengganu"}
{"question": "Xikers (Korean: 싸이커스; RR: Ssaikeoseu; stylized in all lowercase) is a South Korean boy band formed by KQ Entertainment. The group consists of ten members: Minjae, Junmin, Sumin, Jinsik, Hyunwoo, Junghoon,", "answer": "Seeun,"}
{"question": "Spargo are a Dutch band, formed in 1975, known for their hits \"You and Me\", \"Head Up to the Sky\", \"One Night Affair\", \"Just For You\" and \"Hip Hap Hop\" in", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 2023 Asian Women's Club Volleyball Championship is the 23rd edition of the Asian Women's Club Volleyball Championship, an annual international women's volleyball club tournament organized by the Asian Volleyball Confederation", "answer": "(AVC)"}
{"question": "Mister Global 2022 was the 8th edition of Mister Global pageant, held in Chiang Mai, Thailand on February 11, 2023. Danh Chiếu Linh of Vietnam crowned Juan Carlos Ariosa of Cuba", "answer": "as"}
{"question": "The Filó Case refers to the theft, robbery and animal cruelty against a capybara, which occurred on April 29, 2023, when the Agenor Tupinambá was falsely denounced by Luisa Mell, that", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 2022–23 Australian bushfire season was the season of summer bushfires in Australia. The outlook for the season was below average in coastal parts of south-eastern Australia due high rainfall associated", "answer": "with"}
{"question": "The Electoral Commission (An Coimisiún Toghcháin) is an election commission with responsibility for the oversight of all elections in Ireland, including electoral operations, constituency reviews and electoral integrity. It was established", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "NCT DoJaeJung (Korean: 엔시티 도재정; RR: Ensiti Dojaejeong; stylized as all caps) is the fifth sub-unit of the South Korean boy band NCT, formed and managed by SM Entertainment. The group", "answer": "consists"}
{"question": "The 2023 Saudi Arabian Grand Prix (officially known as the Formula 1 STC Saudi Arabian Grand Prix 2023) was a Formula One motor race that was held on 19 March 2023", "answer": "at"}
{"question": "The 43rd Golden Raspberry Awards, or Razzies, honored the worst the film industry had to offer in 2022 on March 10, 2023. The awards were based on votes from members of", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 59th Baeksang Arts Awards (Korean: 제59회 백상예술대상) ceremony, organised by Ilgan Sports and JTBC Plus, was held at Incheon Paradise City, Incheon on April 28, 2023, at 17:30 KST. The", "answer": "event"}
{"question": "The 2023 Rebellion was a professional wrestling pay-per-view (PPV) event produced by Impact Wrestling. It took place on April 16, 2023, at the Rebel Entertainment Complex in Toronto, Ontario, Canada. It", "answer": "was"}
{"question": "The Anti-Homosexuality Bill, 2023 is a Ugandan parliamentary bill that restricts freedom of speech on LGBT topics and criminalises homosexuality. On 21 March 2023, the bill was read a third time,", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "The Recovering America's Wildlife Act (RAWA) is a bill in the United States Congress intended to provide funding for the conservation of wildlife in the United States. In the 117th United", "answer": "States"}
{"question": "The 2023 Nobel Prize in Literature is an international literary prize established according to Alfred Nobel's will that will be announced by the Swedish Academy in Stockholm, Sweden, on 5 October", "answer": "2023"}
{"question": "On January 19, 2023, the United States hit its debt ceiling, beginning an ongoing debt-ceiling crisis. In response, Janet Yellen, the secretary of the treasury, began enacting temporary \"extraordinary measures\". The", "answer": "crisis"}
{"question": "The 35th Lo Nuestro Awards were held at the Dade Arena in Miami on February 23, 2023, to recognize the most popular Spanish-language music of 2022. The ceremony will be broadcast", "answer": "on"}
{"question": "The 2023 Nigerian currency crisis was precipitated by a shortage of cash currency (the naira) and an attempt by the Nigerian government to force citizens to use a newly created government-sponsored", "answer": "central"}
{"question": "The 20th Korean Music Awards was held in Seoul, South Korea on March 5, 2023. Hosted by the Korean Music Awards Selection Committee and sponsored by the Ministry of Culture, Sports", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "Local elections are scheduled to be held in Sri Lanka in 2023. More than 16.6 million Sri Lankans will be eligible to elect 8,711 members to 340 local authorities comprising 24", "answer": "Municipal"}
{"question": "The 31st Actors and Actresses Union Awards ceremony was held on 13 March 2023 at the Circo Price in Madrid.In addition to the competitive awards, the Ministry of Equality received the", "answer": "'Mujeres"}
{"question": "The 2023 Salvadoran protests occurred on 1 May 2023 in San Salvador, El Salvador. Protestors marched from the Cuscatlán Park to the Gerardo Barrios Plaza in protest of the 2022–23 gang", "answer": "crackdown"}
{"question": "The 2023 Africa Magic Viewers' Choice Awards is scheduled to hold between 18 and 20 May 2023. The event will include a series of pre-show activities with the actual award show", "answer": "set"}
{"question": "Miss Teen USA 2023 will be the 41st Miss Teen USA pageant that will be held in 2023 at the Grand Sierra Resort in Reno, Nevada. Faron Medhi of Nebraska will", "answer": "crown"}
{"question": "Supriyo a.k.a Supriya Chakraborty & Abhay Dang v. Union of India thr. Its Secretary, Ministry of Law and Justice & other connected cases (2023) is an ongoing collection of landmark cases", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 2023 San Miguel Corporation (SMC) - Philippine Sportswriters Association (PSA) Annual Awards was an annual awarding ceremony honoring the individuals (athletes, teams, officials and organizations) and organizations that made a", "answer": "significant"}
{"question": "Two motions of no confidence in the minority government of Prime Minister Élisabeth Borne were tabled on 17 March 2023 in the French National Assembly. One motion was proposed by a", "answer": "cross-party"}
{"question": "General elections are scheduled to be held in Luxembourg by October 2023. All 60 seats of the Chamber of Deputies will be renewed. The incumbent Bettel–Schneider Ministry is a coalition of", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "Demonstrations took place in the city of Sinjar, located west of Mosul, the capital of Nineveh Governorate, after dozens of Arab families returned to the town, some of them believed to", "answer": "have"}
{"question": "The 2023 All In, also known as All in London at Wembley Stadium, is the upcoming second All In professional wrestling pay-per-view (PPV) event. It will be the first edition of", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "Operation Kaveri (Hindi: कावेरी, romanized: Kaveri, lit. Kaveri River) is an ongoing operation conducted by the Indian Armed Forces to evacuate Indian citizens and foreign nationals from Sudan during the 2023", "answer": "Sudan"}
{"question": "On 4 January 2023, newly-appointed Israeli Justice Minister Yariv Levin announced his intention to make a number of major changes to the judicial system and the balance of powers in Israel.", "answer": "On"}
{"question": "Miss Grand Vietnam 2023 will be the second edition of the Miss Grand Vietnam beauty pageant, scheduled to be held in Ho Chi Minh City on August 26, 2023. National finalists", "answer": "qualified"}
{"question": "On April 6, dozens of rockets were fired from Lebanon into Israel, wounding 3 Israeli civilians. The IDF has said that it has intercepted 25 rockets fired from Lebanon. Warning sirens", "answer": "had"}
{"question": "Miss Grand Peru 2023 will be the inaugural edition of the Miss Grand Peru beauty pageant. Twelve candidates who qualified for the pageant through a virtual casting held earlier in January", "answer": "will"}
{"question": "Everything for Chile (Spanish: Todo por Chile) is a Chilean electoral alliance formed in February 2023 to present candidacies for the 2023 Chilean Constitutional Council election that will be held on", "answer": "7"}
{"question": "Zerobaseone (Korean: 제로베이스원; RR: Jerobeiseuwon, stylized in all caps; abbreviated as ZB1) is a South Korean boy group formed through Mnet's reality competition Boys Planet in 2023. It is managed by", "answer": "Wake"}
{"question": "Armenia is set to participate in the Eurovision Song Contest 2023 in Liverpool, United Kingdom, having internally selected Brunette to represent the country with the song \"Future Lover\". Brunette was announced", "answer": "as"}
{"question": "Many countries allocated relief aid items to southern Africa after Cyclone Freddy, with a main focus on the humanitarian crisis in Malawi. Items included hygiene supplies, food rations, and safe drinking", "answer": "water"}
{"question": "On 17 March 2023, as part of its investigation, the International Criminal Court (ICC) issued arrest warrants for Vladimir Putin, the President of Russia, and Maria Lvova-Belova, Russian Commissioner for Children's", "answer": "Rights,"}
{"question": "Slovenia is set to participate in the Eurovision Song Contest 2023 in Liverpool, United Kingdom, having internally selected Joker Out to represent the country with the song \"Carpe Diem\", written by", "answer": "band"}
{"question": "Latvia is set to participate in the Eurovision Song Contest 2023 in Liverpool, United Kingdom, with \"Aijā\" performed by Sudden Lights. The Latvian broadcaster Latvijas Televīzija (LTV) organised the national selection", "answer": "Supernova"}
{"question": "For Tracy Hyde was a Japanese shoegaze band, formed in 2012. The group started as the solo project of Natsubot, real name Azusa Suga, before adding more members over time. It", "answer": "consisted"}
{"question": "This article is about the 2023 flower protests in Russia. There have also been other flower protests, e.g. in Myanmar in 2021 on Suu Kyi's 76th birthday Flower protests are a", "answer": "wave"}
{"question": "The 2023 German public transport strike was a nationwide labor strike that occurred in March 2023 in Germany. The strike was organized by Ver.di and EVG, two major transport unions, who", "answer": "demanded"}
{"question": "Parliamentary elections were held in Turkmenistan on 26 March 2023 to elect the 125 members of the Assembly. The elections took place after the introduction of a separate constitutional authority. The", "answer": "Assembly"}
{"question": "The 2023 Money in the Bank is the upcoming 14th annual Money in the Bank professional wrestling pay-per-view (PPV) and livestreaming event produced by the American promotion WWE. It will be", "answer": "held"}
{"question": "The 40th Robert Awards ceremony, presented by Danish Film Academy on 4 February 2023, to honour the best in Danish film and television of 2022. The ceremony took place at the", "answer": "Tivoli"}
{"question": "2023 International Conference on Climate Resilient Pakistan, more commonly referred to as 2023 Geneva conference, was a one-day international conference on aid to Pakistani Government after the devastating floods in 2022.", "answer": "The"}
{"question": "The 2022–23 Bangladesh Championship League is the 11th season of the Bangladesh Championship League since its establishment in 2012. A total of 11 football clubs will be competing in the league.Fortis", "answer": "FC"}
{"question": "The 2022–23 Toronto Raptors season was the 28th season of the franchise in the National Basketball Association (NBA). Finishing the season as the ninth seed in the Eastern Conference, the Raptors", "answer": "qualified"}
{"question": "On 24 February 2022, Russia invaded and occupied parts of Ukraine in a major escalation of the Russo-Ukrainian War, which had begun in 2014. The invasion has resulted in tens of", "answer": "thousands"}
{"question": "On February 6, 2023, the China Coast Guard and Philippine Coast Guard had an encounter near the Second Thomas Shoal, one of the features of the Spratly Islands which is subject", "answer": "to"}
{"question": "The 95th Academy Awards was a ceremony held by the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences (AMPAS) on March 12, 2023, at the Dolby Theatre in Los Angeles, which honored", "answer": "films"}
{"question": "The 2023 South African National Shutdown was a protest held by the political party EFF on 20 March 2023, the day before Human Rights Day. The EFF called for the resignation", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "Conveyor belt sushi (Japanese: 回転寿司, Hepburn: kaiten-zushi), also called rotation sushi, is a type of sushi restaurant common in Japan. In Australasia, it is also known as a sushi train. Plates", "answer": "serving"}
{"question": "The 30th Hanteo Music Awards (Korean: 30주년 한터뮤직어워즈 2022; RR: 30junyeon Hanteomyujigeowojeu 2022; lit. 30th Anniversary Hanteo Music Awards 2022) ceremony is currently held at Jamsil Arena in Seoul on February", "answer": "10–11,"}
{"question": "The Special Honours Lists for Australia are announced by the Sovereign and Governor-General at any time. Some honours are awarded by other countries where King Charles III is the Head of", "answer": "State"}
{"question": "Malta is set to participate in the Eurovision Song Contest 2023 in Liverpool, United Kingdom. The Maltese entry for the 2023 contest will be performed by the band the Busker, who", "answer": "won"}
{"question": "The Battle of Khartoum is an ongoing battle for control of Khartoum, the capital of Sudan, between the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces (RSF), and the Sudanese Armed Forces. The battle began", "answer": "on"}
{"question": "A series of changes to the judicial system and the balance of powers in Israel was proposed in January 2023. The effort has been spearheaded by Deputy Prime Minister and Minister", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 15th Selangor state election will be held in 2023 to elect the State Assembly members of the 15th Selangor State Legislative Assembly, the legislature of the Malaysian state of Selangor.", "answer": "Selangor"}
{"question": "On April 17, 2023, a robbery occurred at Toronto Pearson International Airport in Canada, with over C$20 million (US$15 million) worth of gold and other high-value items being stolen. A container", "answer": "arrived"}
{"question": "Miss Belgium 2023 was the 55th edition of the Miss Belgium pageant, held on February 11, 2023, at the Plopsaland Theater in De Panne, Belgium. Because of the absence of reigning", "answer": "Miss"}
{"question": "Advanced Land Observing Satellite 3 (ALOS-3), also called Daichi 3, was a 3-ton Japanese satellite launched on March 7 2023. It was to succeed the optical sensor PRISM (Panchromatic Remote-sensing Instruments", "answer": "for"}
{"question": "Axiom Mission 3 (or Ax-3) is a planned private spaceflight to the International Space Station. The flight, scheduled to launch no earlier than November 2023, will be operated by Axiom Space", "answer": "and"}
{"question": "The 2023 Berlin repeat state election was held on 12 February 2023 to once again elect the 19th Abgeordnetenhaus of Berlin. The 19th Abgeordnetenhaus was originally elected on 26 September 2021.", "answer": "On"}
{"question": "The 2023 EuroLeague Playoffs, known as the 2023 Turkish Airlines EuroLeague Playoffs for sponsorship purposes, will be the first postseason portion of the 2022–23 EuroLeague basketball competition. They will begin on", "answer": "25"}
{"question": "Since the beginning of 2022, multiple unusual deaths of Russian businesspeople or high officials, sometimes including their family members, have occurred under what some sources suggest were suspicious circumstances, evidencing the", "answer": "dire"}
{"question": "A concert and rally took place on 22 February 2023 at Luzhniki Stadium in Moscow. TASS reported that the rally commemorated Defender of the Fatherland Day. Ukrainska Pravda stated that the", "answer": "date"}
{"question": "Binibining Pilipinas 2023 will be the 59th edition of Binibining Pilipinas to be held on May 28, 2023 at the Smart Araneta Coliseum in Quezon City, Metro Manila, Philippines.At the end", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "The 1st Hollywood Critics Association Creative Arts Awards, presented by the Hollywood Critics Association, took place on February 24, 2023. The winners were announced on the official HCA Facebook, Instagram and", "answer": "Twitter,"}
{"question": "Global news flow (also referred to as international news flow) is a field of study that deals with the news coverage of events in foreign countries. It describes and explains the", "answer": "flow"}
{"question": "Parliamentary elections are scheduled to be held in East Timor on 21 May 2023. The current governing coalition is a four-party government of Fretilin–PLP–KHUNTO–PD, whilst CNRT is in opposition and holds", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "United Nations Security Council Resolution 2673 was passed by a unanimous vote on 11 January 2023, which extended the United Nations Verification Mission in Colombia and reaffirmed commitment to the Colombian", "answer": "peace"}
{"question": "The Honduran gang crackdown, referred to in Honduras as the Régimen de Excepción (Spanish for State of Exception), began in December 2022 after parts of the constitution were suspended to fight", "answer": "criminal"}
{"question": "The 2023 Omnibus Law on Job Creation is replacement of the Omnibus Law on Job Creation. The law is passed by the People's Representative Council on 21 March 2023. The law", "answer": "commenced"}
{"question": "A hybrid solar eclipse occurred on Thursday, April 20, 2023. A solar eclipse occurs when the Moon passes between Earth and the Sun thereby totally or partly obscuring the Sun for", "answer": "a"}
{"question": "Serbia is set to participate in the Eurovision Song Contest 2023 in Liverpool, United Kingdom, with \"Samo mi se spava\" performed by Luke Black. The Serbian national broadcaster, Radio Television of", "answer": "Serbia"}
{"question": "The 2022–2023 mpox outbreak in South America is a part of the outbreak of human mpox caused by the West African clade of the monkeypox virus. The outbreak reached South America", "answer": "on"}
{"question": "The 2023 Swiss federal election will be held on 22 October 2023 to elect all members of the National Council and Council of States of Switzerland. It will be followed by", "answer": "elections"}
{"question": "The 2023 Libera Awards will be held on June 15, 2023, to recognize the best in independent music of 2022 presented by the American Association of Independent Music. The ceremony will", "answer": "take"}
{"question": "General elections are expected to be held in the Democratic Republic of the Congo on 20 December 2023 according to the electoral calendar released 26 November 2022 by the Independent National", "answer": "Electoral"}
{"question": "The 41st Hong Kong Film Awards presentation ceremony took place at Hong Kong Cultural Centre on 16 April 2023. Nominations were announced on 9 February 2023. The Sparring Partner received 16", "answer": "nominations"}
{"question": "Cold Water Flat was an American band formed in 1990 by Paul Janovitz (vocals and guitar), Ted Silva (bass) and Paul Harding (drums) when the trio studied at University of Massachusetts", "answer": "Amherst."}
{"question": "Team Jorge is the name given to an outfit of Israeli contractors specialized in the use of malign cyber activities including hacking, sabotage and bot farm-run social media disinformation campaigns to", "answer": "manipulate"}
{"question": "The 2023 Summer Metro Manila Film Festival is an ongoing iteration of the annual Summer Metro Manila Film Festival held in Metro Manila and throughout the Philippines. It is to be", "answer": "organized"}
{"question": "The 28th Edition of Star Awards 2023 (Chinese: 红星大奖2023) is a television award ceremony that honoured the best in Singaporean television released between January and December 2022. Star Awards 2023 prepares", "answer": "for"}
{"question": "The 18th Canadian Folk Music Awards will be presented between March 31 and April 2, 2023, to honour achievements in folk music by Canadian artists in 2022. Nominees were announced in", "answer": "October"}
{"question": "The Hana Kimura Memorial Show 3 (木村花メモリアルマッチ『またね』, Kimura Hana Memoriaru Matchi \"Matane\" 3) is the upcoming third Japanese professional wrestling memorial show and pay-per-view event promoted by Kyoko Kimura to commemorate", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 2023 Toronto Blue Jays season is the 47th season of the Toronto Blue Jays franchise, and the Blue Jays’ 32nd full season (34th overall) at Rogers Centre. They started the", "answer": "season"}
{"question": "The 2023 Brazil–China summit was a four-day state visit by Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva, the President of Brazil, to China from 11 to 14 April 2023. It was Lula's first", "answer": "visit"}
{"question": "Femina Miss India 2023 was the 59th edition of the Femina Miss India beauty pageant. After a two-year hiatus, the entire processes of the competition from audition to the final was", "answer": "held"}
{"question": "The 2023 Las Anod conflict is an ongoing armed conflict between the Somaliland National Army and militias of the Dhulbahante, Majeerteen and Warsangali clans that ensued in Las Anod, the capital", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "Berlin 2030 klimaneutral (English: Berlin 2030 climate-neutral) was a citizens' initiative launched in Berlin in 2018. It was the subject of a city-wide referendum scheduled for 26 March 2023, commonly called", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "The 2023 Hong Kong District Council elections are scheduled in November 2023 for all 18 District Councils of Hong Kong. They were the first local elections after the passage of the", "answer": "national"}
{"question": "By late 2022, the price of red and white onions in the Philippines increased significantly, reaching an all-time high in December at ₱700 per kilogram and leading people to smuggle the", "answer": "commodity"}
{"question": "The Raluca case refers to the crime of ideological fraud that took place on March 31, 2023, when a Raluca impersonated another Jena L. The case had national and international repercussions.Raluca", "answer": "was"}
{"question": "The Windsor Framework is a proposed post-Brexit legal agreement between the European Union and the United Kingdom which was announced on 27 February 2023. It is designed to address the problem", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "A crisis at the National Public Health Laboratory in Khartoum, Sudan, started after it was seized by armed forces during the Sudan conflict in April 2023. The World Health Organization (WHO)", "answer": "said"}
{"question": "SpaceX Crew-7 is planned to be the seventh crewed operational NASA Commercial Crew flight of a Crew Dragon spacecraft, and the eleventh overall crewed orbital flight. The mission is planned for", "answer": "launch"}
{"question": "Progress MS-22 (Russian: Прогресс МC-22), Russian production No.452, identified by NASA as Progress 83P, is a Progress spaceflight launched by Roscosmos to resupply the International Space Station (ISS). It is the", "answer": "175th"}
{"question": "Miss Universe 2023 will be the 72nd Miss Universe pageant, to be held in 2023 in El Salvador. R'Bonney Gabriel of the United States will crown her successor at the end", "answer": "of"}
{"question": "SpaceX CRS-27, also known as SpX-27, was a Commercial Resupply Service mission to the International Space Station (ISS) launched on 15 March 2023. The mission was contracted by NASA and was", "answer": "flown"}
{"question": "On April 10, 2023, a mass shooting occurred at the Old National Bank in Louisville, Kentucky, United States. Five people were killed, and eight others were injured, including two responding police", "answer": "officers."}
{"question": "A rocket attack was carried out at a large bank in Khartoum by the Rapid Support Forces, at around 00:00 AM local time on 30 April 2023, during the civil conflict", "answer": "in"}
{"question": "A constitutional referendum was held in Ecuador on 5 February 2023, alongside the 2023 Ecuadorian local elections. The binding consultation was called on 29 November 2022 by President Guillermo Lasso. Voters", "answer": "were"}
{"question": "Russkaja (stylized as ЯUSSKAJA) were a ska punk band from Vienna, Austria. The band calls its sound \"Russian Turbo Polka Metal.\" It has drawn on polka, ska, fanfare, pop, rock, and", "answer": "traditional"}
{"question": "Iceberg A-81 is an iceberg that calved from the Brunt Ice Shelf in January 2023. The detachment happened near the British-operated Halley Research Station, which is located only 20 km away", "answer": "from"}
{"question": "General elections were held in Antigua and Barbuda on 18 January 2023 to elect members of the House of Representatives. The Labour Party (ABLP) has held an absolute majority of 15", "answer": "seats"}
{"question": "Music Awards Ceremony (MAC) 2023, presented by Sky Music, was held on 25 and 26 January 2023 to recognize the best in the music of former Yugoslav countries. The ceremony took", "answer": "place"}
{"question": "Hidden Treasures Dabur Vatika Shampoo Miss Nepal 2023, the 27th Miss Nepal beauty pageant will be held on 27 May 2023 at the Godavari Sunrise Convention Center, at Godawari, Lalitpur. Miss", "answer": "Nepal"}
{"question": "The murder of Jacqueline Montgomery, a 15-year-old girl from Islington, North London, United Kingdom, occurred on 1 June 1975. She was murdered by Dennis McGrory, her aunt's 28-year-old estranged partner, who", "answer": "was"}
{"question": "As part of the British honours system, Special Honours are issued at the Monarch's pleasure at any given time. The Special Honours refer to the awards made within royal prerogative, operational", "answer": "honours,"}
{"question": "Unity for Chile (Spanish: Unidad para Chile) is a Chilean electoral alliance formed in February 2023 to present candidacies for the Chilean Constitutional Council election that will be held on 7", "answer": "May"}
{"question": "The 14th National People's Congress is the current meeting of the legislative branch and, constitutionally, the supreme authority of the People's Republic of China. It convened in Beijing, on 5 March", "answer": "2023,"}
{"question": "The SIM Registration Act, officially designated as Republic Act No. 11934 and commonly referred to as the SIM card law, is a Philippine law mandating the registration of SIM cards before", "answer": "activation."}
{"question": "Presidential elections are scheduled to be held in the Maldives on Monday 9 September 2023. Incumbent president Ibrahim Mohamed Solih will be seeking re-election, after defeating Speaker of the People's Majlis", "answer": "Mohamed"}
{"question": "Protests at several locations in Ireland started in early November 2022 after the development of sites in various parts of the country as temporary refugee shelters by the Department of Children,", "answer": "Equality,"}
{"question": "A constitutional referendum was held in Uzbekistan on 30 April 2023. It was to be held on proposed constitutional amendments.Parliament approved the referendum on 15 March 2023. It was accepted in", "answer": "the"}
{"question": "General elections will be held in Guatemala on 25 June 2023 to elect the president and vice president, all 160 seats of the Congress, all 20 members of the Central American", "answer": "Parliament,"}
{"question": "The Stone Coyotes are an American band that debuted with their first album in 1998. They hail from Massachusetts but tour primarily in Texas as that is where they receive their", "answer": "most"}
{"question": "The 2023 France–China summit was a three-day state visit by Emmanuel Macron, the President of France, to China from April 5 to 7, 2023. It was Macron's first visit to China", "answer": "since"}
{"question": "The 6th Hollywood Critics Association Film Awards, presented by the Hollywood Critics Association, took place on the evening of February 24, 2023 at the Beverly Wilshire Hotel, Beverly Hills, while the", "answer": "winners"}
{"question": "The XI Gay Games 2023, also known as Gay Games 11, GGHK2023, GGGDL2023 and Hong Kong - Guadalajara Gay Games 2023, is an upcoming international multi-sport event and cultural gathering organised", "answer": "by,"}
{"question": "Miss Earth 2023 will be the 23rd Miss Earth pageant to be held in 2023 in Nha Trang, Khánh Hòa, Vietnam. Mina Sue Choi of South Korea will crown her successor", "answer": "at"}
{"question": "Elections to the Assembly of French Polynesia are scheduled to be held on 16 and 30 April 2023 in order to elect 57 representatives to the Assembly of French Polynesia. The", "answer": "last"}
{"question": "The 2023 Open Comunidad de Madrid was a professional tennis tournament played on clay courts. It was the 2nd edition of the tournament which was part of the 2023 ATP Challenger", "answer": "Tour."}
{"question": "In April 2023, two sets of classified foreign intelligence documents of the United States began circulating on Twitter, Telegram, and 4chan. Jack Teixeira, an airman first class of the Massachusetts Air", "answer": "National"}
{"question": "On 22 February 2023, Israel conducted a military incursion into the Palestinian city of Nablus. After an undercover unit located the house in which two militants were believed to be residing,", "answer": "a"}
{"question": "The 16th Houston Film Critics Society Awards were announced on February 18, 2023, at the Midtown Arts & Theater Center Houston (MATCH) in Texas. The nominations were announced on January 10,", "answer": "2023,"}
{"question": "The 2023 Rey de Reyes (Spanish for \"2023 King of Kings\") was a professional wrestling tournament and supercard event produced by the Mexican Lucha Libre AAA Worldwide (AAA) promotion. The event", "answer": "was"}
{"question": "Cyclones Judy and Kevin were a pair of intense tropical cyclones that made landfall on the Pacific island nation of Vanuatu within 48 hours of each other in March 2023. They", "answer": "were"}
